Contact

917-330-1630 (Mobile) vpetitwork@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/vanessapetit-662b3172 (LinkedIn) vanessapetit.com (Personal)

Top Skills

Copy Editing
Proofreading
Spanish-English

Languages

Spanish (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications COVID-19 Contact Tracing

Vanessa Petit

Copywriter and Spanish translator at The Avon Company New York

Summary

I have over 20 years of experience producing content across many platforms: print, online and video in both English and Spanish. I'm a versatile writer, editor and translator with a broad background which allows me to tackle many subjects. I have a special interest in beauty, fashion, health, travel, culture, education and parenting. For more information: www.vanessapetit.com

Experience

The Avon Company
Copywriter and Spanish translator
October 2020 - Present (1 year 2 months)
New York

Responsible for creating product descriptions for all marketing materials such as brochures, pamphlets, flyers and digital platforms. Translated copy from English to Spanish to ensure error free content and cultural relevance and consistency. Proofread all materials.

Marriott Bonvoy Traveler
Freelance Writer
January 2020 - Present (1 year 11 months)
New York, United States

Write Latin American travel features for their Spanish language website.

StoryTerrace
Interviewer/ Ghostwriter
November 2019 - Present (2 years 1 month)
New York, United States

Interview customers who want to capture their life stories for their families, friends and/or employees. I conduct hours of interviews in English and/or Spanish and write their memoirs.

Common Sense Media Translator December 2019 - October 2020 (11 months)

New York, United States

Translated from English to Spanish movie, TV shows and book reviews to be included on their website.

Moroccan Oil

Freelance Translator

January 2016 - February 2017 (1 year 2 months)

Moroccan Oil- English to Spanish translation of product copy for Spanish language website, advertisements, hand books.

What to Expect- Everyday Health Freelance Hispanic Editor February 2016 - June 2016 (5 months) New York

Developed a package of articles for millennial Latina moms on parenting, biculturalism, bilingualism and heritage on their whattoexpect.com site.

Latina Media Ventures Interim Managing Editor September 2015 - December 2015 (4 months) New York

In charge of the production workflow of the February issue between editors, writers, and advertising department. Responsible for maintaining and updating the February, March and April lineups, assigning stories to freelance writers, sending out contracts, budgets and editing copy throughout the routing process.

Meredith Corporation
Deputy Editor
January 2006 - March 2015 (9 years 3 months)
New York city

Content creation: Responsible for editorial content of all three publications: Ser Padres, Bebé and Espera, ensuring cultural relevance and balance. Produced and wrote for many different sections: Beauty, Goody Bag, Fashion, Health, Travel, Development, Culture features and First Person pieces. Contributed ideas for Fashion photo shoots and collaborated with the Art department on the production from start to finish. Spearheaded our Celebrity Covers by finding and ensuring the talent. Collaborated writing posts for the website.

Production: Worked with the Editor-in-Chief to lead the planning and execution of the editorial material, including the writing, editing and adherence to production schedules for print editions.

Administration: Created yearly and monthly editorial calendars. Commissioned editorial concepts to freelance writers. Worked with marketing on several partnership ideas.

Representation: Assisted presentations, roundtables and various different events to speak to potential clients about the brand. Provided the public presence for the Ser Padres brand at industry functions such as the Toy Fair and the ABC Expo every year and with the media doing segments with Telemundo, Univision and CNN en español.

Special Skills:

Working Knowledge of InDesign and Photoshop.

Translation English to Spanish; Spanish to English
Native Spanish and English speaker
Working Knowledge of Wordpress

Associated Press

3 years

Reporter

May 2005 - September 2005 (5 months)

New York City Area

Updated the AP Spanish website, translating and editing content from English to Spanish. Posted photos, edited and translated captions. Created short headlines. Covered and wrote entertainment news for the website.

Editorial Assistant

October 2002 - April 2005 (2 years 7 months)

Supported the editorial staff. Responsibilities included reporting and covering local news and writing spot news and enterprise stories. Administrative duties such as updating the daily calendar of events and assisting news meetings and helping out writers and editors with research and access to local contacts.

Los Angeles Times
Editorial assistant/ reporter/ stringer / translator

December 1998 - September 2002 (3 years 10 months)

Buenos Aires, Argentina

Assistant reporter and researcher to Bureau Chief responsible for news coverage of seven South American countries. Reported, researched and collaborated in the writing of many news stories in the region.

Education

Pontificia Universidad Católica Argentina 'Santa María de los Buenos Aires'

Bachelor's Degree, Communication, Journalism, and Related Programs · (1999 - 2002)

Universidad de Belgrano

Master's Degree, Political Science and Government · (1992 - 1997)